<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Seneca on Hugo Prose</title>
    <link>/tags/seneca/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Seneca on Hugo Prose</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/seneca/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Letter 4: On The Terrors of Death</title>
      <link>/post/2019/07/30/letter-4-on-the-terrors-of-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/07/30/letter-4-on-the-terrors-of-death/</guid>
      <description>Keep on as you have begun, and make all possible haste, so that you may have longer enjoyment of an improved mind, one that is at peace with itself.
Doubtless you will derive enjoyment during the time when you are improving your mind and setting it at peace with itself; but quite different is the pleasure which comes from contemplation when one’s mind is so cleansed from every stain that it shines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter 2: On Discursiveness in Reading</title>
      <link>/post/2016/02/14/letter-2-on-discursiveness-in-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016/02/14/letter-2-on-discursiveness-in-reading/</guid>
      <description>Judging by what you write me, and by what I hear, I am forming a good opinion regarding your future.
You do not run hither and thither and distract yourself by changing your abode; for such restlessness is the sign of a disordered spirit.
The primary indication, to my thinking, of a well-ordered mind is a man’s ability to remain in one place and linger in his own company.
Be careful, however, lest this reading of many authors and books of every sort may tend to make you discursive and unsteady.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter 1: On Saving Time</title>
      <link>/post/2015/07/23/letter-1-on-saving-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015/07/23/letter-1-on-saving-time/</guid>
      <description>Greetings from Seneca to his friend Lucilius.
Continue to act thus, my dear Lucilius – set yourself free for your own sake; gather and save your time, which till lately has been forced from you, or filched away, or has merely slipped from your hands.
Make yourself believe the truth of my words, that certain moments are torn from us, that some are gently removed, and that others glide beyond our reach.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
